<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xml:id="chap-usage">

	<title>Usage</title>

	<para>
		The <filename>deployment/DistributedDeployment</filename> contains all
		neccessary Disnix models, such as a services, infrastructure and distribution
		models required for deployment.
	</para>
	
	<section>
		<title>Deployment in a heterogeneous network</title>
		
		<para>
			For this scenario only installation of the basic Disnix toolset is required.
			First, you must manually install a network of machines running the Disnix service.
			Then you must adapt the infrastructure model to match to properties of your network
			and the distribution model to map the services to the right machines.
			To deploy the databases you must install
			<link xlink:href="http://www.mysql.com">MySQL</link>.
			To deploy the web services and web application services you must install 
			<link xlink:href="http://tomcat.apache.org">Apache Tomcat</link>.
			Check the instructions of your Linux distribution or the software distributions
			themselves how to install these system services.
			The Disnix activation scripts detect the presence of these system services
			and configures the activation scripts to use them.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			The system can be deployed by running the following command:
<screen>
$ disnix-env -s services-simple.nix -i infrastructure.nix -d distribution-simple.nix
</screen>
		</para>
		
		<para>
			The <filename>service-simple.nix</filename> and <filename>distribution-simple.nix</filename> files
			can be replaced by the models for the other variants, such as <filename>service-lookup.nix</filename>.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Deployment using DisnixOS</title>
		
		<para>
			For this scenario you need to install a network of NixOS machines, running the
			Disnix service. This can be done by enabling the following configuration
			option in each <filename>/etc/nixos/configuration.nix</filename> file:
			
<screen>
services.disnix.enable = true;
</screen>
		</para>
		
		<para>
			You may also need to adapt the NixOS configurations to which the
			<filename>network.nix</filename> model is referring, so that they will
			match the actual system configurations.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			The system including its underlying infrastructure can be deployed
			by using the <command>disnixos-env</command> command. The following
			instruction deploys the system including the underlying infrastructure.
			
<screen>
$ disnixos-env -s services.nix -n network.nix -d distribution.nix
</screen>
		</para>
		
		<para>
			The <filename>service-simple.nix</filename> and <filename>distribution-simple.nix</filename> files
			can be replaced by the models for the other variants, such as <filename>service-lookup.nix</filename>.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Deployment using the DisnixOS virtualization feature</title>
		
		<para>
			This system can be deployed without adapting any of the models in
			<filename>deployment/DistributedDeployment</filename>. By running
			the following instruction, the variant without the proxy can be deployed in a network
			of virtual machines:
			
<screen>
$ disnixos-vm-env -s services-simple.nix -n network.nix -d distribution-simple.nix
</screen>
		</para>
		
		<para>
			The <filename>service-simple.nix</filename> and <filename>distribution-simple.nix</filename> files
			can be replaced by the models for the other variants, such as <filename>service-lookup.nix</filename>.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Running the system</title>
		
		<para>
			After the system has been deployed, open a web browser and type the following URL:
			
<screen>
http://<replaceable>hostname</replaceable>:8080/HelloWorld
</screen>
			  
			The <replaceable>hostname</replaceable> part must be replaced by the real hostname of the machine to which
			the web application front-end is deployed. Check the distribution model for this.
			If the network expression is used included in this example, the third machine in the network
			machine automatically boots into IceWM and includes the Mozilla Firefox web browser for
			convenience.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
